<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 21:21:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/</link><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/rss.xml" hreflang="en-us" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/rss.xml" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="application/rss+xml"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/progetti/" hreflang="it-it" rel="canonical" type="text/html"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/progetti/rss.xml" hreflang="it-it" rel="alternate" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Projects · Lorenzo&rsquo;s Notes</title><item><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>AMPHI</strong> is a project that tackles a well-known and frustrating problem in the world of live events: <strong>non-transparent secondary ticketing, scalping, and bot activity</strong> that harm fans, artists, and organizers.</p><h3 id=the-solution-nft-tickets-on-blockchain>The Solution: NFT Tickets on Blockchain</h3><p>The core idea of AMPHI is to transform event tickets into <strong>Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs)</strong> managed on a blockchain (currently tested on Polygon Amoy). This approach allows for the introduction of:</p><ul><li><strong>Transparency:</strong> Each ticket is unique, and its history (issuance, ownership transfers) is traceable on-chain.</li><li><strong>Control:</strong> Rules can be implemented directly in the ticket&rsquo;s smart contract or the marketplace to limit unfair practices.</li><li><strong>New Possibilities:</strong> NFTs open doors to additional experiences for fans (digital collectibles, exclusive content, loyalty mechanisms).</li></ul><h3 id=the-mvp-minimum-viable-product>The MVP (Minimum Viable Product)</h3><p>I have developed a working <strong>MVP (Minimum Viable Product) / Demo</strong> that demonstrates the core functionalities:</p><ol><li><strong>Primary Sale (Minting):</strong> Issuing NFT tickets associated with specific events.</li><li><strong>P2P Secondary Marketplace:</strong> A platform where users can resell their NFT tickets to other users.</li><li><strong>Anti-Scalping Mechanism:</strong> Implementation of a <strong>price cap</strong> in the secondary marketplace to prevent resale at prices higher than the original.</li><li><strong>Wallet Management:</strong> Support for both internally managed wallets (hybrid custodial) and connecting external wallets (e.g., MetaMask).</li></ol><h3 id=technology-stack-overview>Technology Stack (Overview)</h3><p>The project is structured as a <strong>monorepo</strong> and uses:</p><ul><li><strong>Smart Contracts:</strong> Solidity (ERC721 standard) with the Hardhat framework on Polygon Amoy.</li><li><strong>Backend:</strong> REST API built with Node.js and Express, interacts with the blockchain via Ethers.js and manages a PostgreSQL database as an off-chain cache.</li><li><strong>Frontend:</strong> Single Page Application developed with Vue.js 3 and Vite, using Pinia for state management and Axios for API calls.</li></ul><h3 id=current-status-and-code>Current Status and Code</h3><p>The MVP demonstrates the technical feasibility of the concept. Development is ongoing, focusing on integrating payment flows and full support for external wallets.</p><p>The complete source code is publicly available on GitHub:
<strong><a href=https://github.com/modernage12/ticketing-nft/tree/main rel=external>github.com/modernage12/ticketing-nft</a></strong></p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:modernage12.github.io,2025-04-27:/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/amphi/</guid><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/amphi/</link><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/amphi/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/progetti/amphi/" hreflang="it-it" rel="canonical" type="text/html"/><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 21:21:00 +0200</pubDate><title>AMPHI: NFT Ticketing &amp; P2P Marketplace</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>stegoradio</strong> was a collaborative project born with the aim of creating an <strong>online radio and a community for emerging artists</strong> in Salento (Southern Italy).</p><h3 id=objective-and-challenges>Objective and Challenges</h3><p>We wanted to give visibility to local talents and create a gathering space, all with an almost non-existent budget. The main challenge was building awareness and engagement from scratch.</p><h3 id=strategy-and-actions>Strategy and Actions</h3><p>We focused heavily on <strong>Content Marketing</strong> and <strong>Social Media</strong> management, particularly Instagram. Key activities included:</p><ul><li>Production of original content: <strong>Podcasts</strong>, video and written <strong>interviews</strong>, interactive formats.</li><li>Field activities: Conducting <strong>video interviews</strong> on the streets of Lecce.</li><li>Community Management: Constant interaction on Instagram, Telegram, and Discord.</li><li>Event Presence: We secured <strong>sponsorship for a university event</strong> in Lecce, which allowed us to increase visibility.</li><li>Website & YouTube Channel Development.</li></ul><h3 id=results-and-learnings>Results and Learnings</h3><p>Despite limited resources, we managed to:</p><ul><li>Build an <strong>active and interested community</strong>.</li><li>Achieve <strong>significant organic growth</strong> on the Instagram page (around 250 followers).</li><li>Gain local recognition (invitation/sponsorship for the event).</li><li><strong>Key Learning:</strong> I learned firsthand how to develop an effective content marketing strategy on a tight budget, manage social channels for organic growth and engagement, and the importance of community building.</li></ul><p><em>(In parallel, the idea for steghold, an NFT/ticketing marketplace, was born but later shelved due to complexity).</em></p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:modernage12.github.io,2023-05-15:/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/stegoradio/</guid><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/stegoradio/</link><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/stegoradio/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/progetti/stegoradio/" hreflang="it-it" rel="canonical" type="text/html"/><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><title>stegoradio: Community Radio &amp; Content Marketing</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p>During my master&rsquo;s degree period, I started a <strong>personal e-commerce project</strong> focused on the <strong>home automation</strong> sector, with the primary goal of <strong>learning concretely</strong> how to use digital marketing tools and manage an online store.</p><h3 id=objective-and-context>Objective and Context</h3><p>The purpose was not primarily sales, but <strong>&ldquo;getting my hands dirty&rdquo;</strong> with practice, having a <strong>very limited budget</strong> as a student living away from home. I chose the <strong>Shopify</strong> platform for its completeness and widespread use.</p><h3 id=activities-carried-out>Activities Carried Out</h3><ul><li>Creation and configuration of the Shopify store.</li><li>Definition of the marketing and product strategy.</li><li>Implementation and management of <strong>Digital Advertising campaigns on Meta Ads and Google Ads</strong>.</li><li>Performance monitoring via <strong>Google Analytics</strong> and <strong>KPI</strong> analysis.</li><li>Optimization attempts through <strong>A/B testing</strong> and continuous campaign adjustments.</li></ul><h3 id=results-and-learnings>Results and Learnings</h3><ul><li>I gained <strong>direct practical experience</strong> with fundamental tools (Shopify, Google Ads, Meta Ads, GA).</li><li>I learned to manage campaigns with reduced budgets, focusing on optimization.</li><li>I came <strong>close to the first sale</strong>, lost only due to an error in configuring shipping costs (an important lesson learned!).</li><li>The experiment <strong>achieved the learning objective</strong>, providing me with solid practical foundations in performance marketing and e-commerce management.</li></ul>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:modernage12.github.io,2022-10-20:/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/ecommerce-shopify/</guid><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/ecommerce-shopify/</link><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/ecommerce-shopify/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/progetti/ecommerce-shopify/" hreflang="it-it" rel="canonical" type="text/html"/><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><title>E-commerce Experiment: Home Automation &amp; Performance Ads</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>polka clothing</strong> started as a fun little experiment in <strong>micro-entrepreneurship</strong> and <strong>branding</strong> in the world of <strong>vintage clothing reselling</strong>, conducted with a friend.</p><h3 id=the-idea>The Idea</h3><p>We bought unique clothing items at flea markets and resold them on the <strong>Vinted</strong> platform. The goal was not just to sell, but to create a small, recognizable brand and offer a quality experience.</p><h3 id=branding-and-marketing>Branding and Marketing</h3><p>We created the &ldquo;<strong>polka clothing</strong>&rdquo; brand from scratch, defining:</p><ul><li>A <strong>style</strong> and a coordinated image.</li><li>A specific <strong>tone of voice</strong> for communication.</li><li>A dedicated <strong>Instagram page</strong> (<a href=https://www.instagram.com/polka_clothing/ rel=external><strong>@polka_clothing</strong></a>
) to showcase items and interact.</li></ul><h3 id=customer-experience>Customer Experience</h3><p>Particular attention was paid to the post-purchase experience, taking care of the <strong>packaging</strong> and adding small details like personalized <strong>candies and thank-you notes</strong>.</p><h3 id=result>Result</h3><p>Despite being a small-scale project (&ldquo;small satisfactions&rdquo;), polka clothing was a formative and fun experience that allowed us to concretely apply principles of branding, social media marketing, e-commerce, and customer care in a real context.</p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:modernage12.github.io,2022-05-10:/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/polka-vinted/</guid><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/polka-vinted/</link><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/polka-vinted/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/progetti/polka-vinted/" hreflang="it-it" rel="canonical" type="text/html"/><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><title>polka clothing: Micro-Branding &amp; Vintage Reselling on Vinted</title></item><item><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the project for the creation and continuous development of my personal website/portfolio, the digital space you are in now! It was built using the static site generator <strong>Hugo</strong> and the <strong>Paige</strong> theme.</p><h3 id=objective>Objective:</h3><p>To create an online space to present myself more completely than a traditional CV, showing work and educational experiences, personal projects, interests, and skills in a dynamic and authentic way.</p><h3 id=technologies-and-tools-used>Technologies and Tools Used:</h3><ul><li><strong>Static Site Generator:</strong> Hugo (v0.141.0 Extended)</li><li><strong>Theme:</strong> Paige (integrated as a Git Submodule)</li><li><strong>Content Language:</strong> Markdown with TOML Front Matter</li><li><strong>Hosting:</strong> GitHub Pages (configured for free deployment)</li><li><strong>Automatic Deployment:</strong> GitHub Actions (custom workflow with <code>peaceiris/actions-gh-pages</code> for build and push to <code>gh-pages</code> branch)</li><li><strong>Build Dependencies:</strong> Dart Sass (installed in the Actions workflow to compile the theme&rsquo;s SCSS)</li><li><strong>Version Control:</strong> Git and GitHub</li><li><strong><code>Analytics: Google Analytics (GA4) for monitoring visits and user behavior.</code></strong></li></ul><h3 id=what-i-learned-and-challenges-overcome>What I Learned and Challenges Overcome:</h3><p>This project has been an excellent training ground for delving into various aspects of web development and modern workflow:</p><ul><li><strong>Advanced Hugo Configuration:</strong> Managing <code>hugo.toml</code>, <code>baseURL</code>, theme parameters ([params.paige], [params.paige.site], [params.paige.subpages]), custom menus, <code>weight</code> management for sorting.</li><li><strong>Content Management:</strong> Structuring in sections (<code>content/</code>), using <code>_index.md</code>, customizing Front Matter for individual pages and sections (e.g., hiding metadata/ToC).</li><li><strong>Theme Customization:</strong> Overriding theme partials (e.g., <code>head.html</code> for GA, <code>site-footer-last.html</code> for social links) to insert custom functionalities while keeping the main theme updatable.</li><li><strong>Static Asset Management:</strong> Using the <code>static</code> folder for files like the CV PDF.</li><li><strong>Automated Deployment:</strong> In-depth configuration and debugging of GitHub Actions, experimenting with different workflows (actions/deploy-pages vs <code>peaceiris/actions-gh-pages</code>), managing permissions (<code>contents: write</code>), and resolving build dependencies in the Actions environment (Hugo versions, Dart Sass installation).</li><li><strong><code>Analytics Integration: Manual implementation of the Google Analytics (GA4) snippet (via override of the Hugo/Paige 'head.html' partial) with the goal of tracking site visits, analyzing user journeys, and collecting aggregated data on the usage of different sections.</code></strong></li><li><strong>Problem Solving:</strong> Addressing and resolving 404 errors (broken links, incomplete deployment), build errors (Hugo/Theme incompatibility, Sass dependencies), permission errors on GitHub Actions.</li><li><strong>Basic HTML/CSS Usage:</strong> Inserting inline HTML (CV link, social icons) and basic styles through theme parameters.</li></ul><h3 id=current-status>Current Status:</h3><p>The site is <strong>currently online</strong> on GitHub Pages and is automatically updated with every <code>push</code> to the <code>master</code> branch of the GitHub repository. It is continuously evolving with the addition of new content and projects.</p><p><em>(Link to Repository: <a href=https://github.com/modernage12/lorenzosnotes rel=external>github.com/modernage12/lorenzosnotes</a>
- you can add it if you want)</em></p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:modernage12.github.io,2025-04-27:/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/sito_personale_hugo/</guid><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/sito_personale_hugo/</link><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/sito_personale_hugo/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/progetti/sito_personale_hugo/" hreflang="it-it" rel="canonical" type="text/html"/><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:55:00 +0200</pubDate><title>Personal Site with Hugo Framework</title></item></channel></rss>