<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 21:21:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/tags/portfolio/</link><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/tags/portfolio/rss.xml" hreflang="en-us" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/tags/portfolio/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/tags/portfolio/rss.xml" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="application/rss+xml"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/tags/portfolio/" hreflang="it-it" rel="canonical" type="text/html"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/tags/portfolio/rss.xml" hreflang="it-it" rel="alternate" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Portfolio · Tags · Lorenzo&rsquo;s Notes</title><item><description><![CDATA[<p>This is the project for the creation and continuous development of my personal website/portfolio, the digital space you are in now! It was built using the static site generator <strong>Hugo</strong> and the <strong>Paige</strong> theme.</p><h3 id=objective>Objective:</h3><p>To create an online space to present myself more completely than a traditional CV, showing work and educational experiences, personal projects, interests, and skills in a dynamic and authentic way.</p><h3 id=technologies-and-tools-used>Technologies and Tools Used:</h3><ul><li><strong>Static Site Generator:</strong> Hugo (v0.141.0 Extended)</li><li><strong>Theme:</strong> Paige (integrated as a Git Submodule)</li><li><strong>Content Language:</strong> Markdown with TOML Front Matter</li><li><strong>Hosting:</strong> GitHub Pages (configured for free deployment)</li><li><strong>Automatic Deployment:</strong> GitHub Actions (custom workflow with <code>peaceiris/actions-gh-pages</code> for build and push to <code>gh-pages</code> branch)</li><li><strong>Build Dependencies:</strong> Dart Sass (installed in the Actions workflow to compile the theme&rsquo;s SCSS)</li><li><strong>Version Control:</strong> Git and GitHub</li><li><strong><code>Analytics: Google Analytics (GA4) for monitoring visits and user behavior.</code></strong></li></ul><h3 id=what-i-learned-and-challenges-overcome>What I Learned and Challenges Overcome:</h3><p>This project has been an excellent training ground for delving into various aspects of web development and modern workflow:</p><ul><li><strong>Advanced Hugo Configuration:</strong> Managing <code>hugo.toml</code>, <code>baseURL</code>, theme parameters ([params.paige], [params.paige.site], [params.paige.subpages]), custom menus, <code>weight</code> management for sorting.</li><li><strong>Content Management:</strong> Structuring in sections (<code>content/</code>), using <code>_index.md</code>, customizing Front Matter for individual pages and sections (e.g., hiding metadata/ToC).</li><li><strong>Theme Customization:</strong> Overriding theme partials (e.g., <code>head.html</code> for GA, <code>site-footer-last.html</code> for social links) to insert custom functionalities while keeping the main theme updatable.</li><li><strong>Static Asset Management:</strong> Using the <code>static</code> folder for files like the CV PDF.</li><li><strong>Automated Deployment:</strong> In-depth configuration and debugging of GitHub Actions, experimenting with different workflows (actions/deploy-pages vs <code>peaceiris/actions-gh-pages</code>), managing permissions (<code>contents: write</code>), and resolving build dependencies in the Actions environment (Hugo versions, Dart Sass installation).</li><li><strong><code>Analytics Integration: Manual implementation of the Google Analytics (GA4) snippet (via override of the Hugo/Paige 'head.html' partial) with the goal of tracking site visits, analyzing user journeys, and collecting aggregated data on the usage of different sections.</code></strong></li><li><strong>Problem Solving:</strong> Addressing and resolving 404 errors (broken links, incomplete deployment), build errors (Hugo/Theme incompatibility, Sass dependencies), permission errors on GitHub Actions.</li><li><strong>Basic HTML/CSS Usage:</strong> Inserting inline HTML (CV link, social icons) and basic styles through theme parameters.</li></ul><h3 id=current-status>Current Status:</h3><p>The site is <strong>currently online</strong> on GitHub Pages and is automatically updated with every <code>push</code> to the <code>master</code> branch of the GitHub repository. It is continuously evolving with the addition of new content and projects.</p><p><em>(Link to Repository: <a href=https://github.com/modernage12/lorenzosnotes rel=external>github.com/modernage12/lorenzosnotes</a>
- you can add it if you want)</em></p>]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:modernage12.github.io,2025-04-27:/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/sito_personale_hugo/</guid><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/sito_personale_hugo/</link><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/en/progetti/sito_personale_hugo/" hreflang="en-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/progetti/sito_personale_hugo/" hreflang="it-it" rel="canonical" type="text/html"/><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 13:55:00 +0200</pubDate><title>Personal Site with Hugo Framework</title></item></channel></rss>