<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web App on</title><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/it/tags/web-app/</link><description>Recent content in Web App on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>it</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 21:21:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/it/tags/web-app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AMPHI: NFT Ticketing &amp; P2P Marketplace</title><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/it/en/progetti/amphi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 21:21:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/it/en/progetti/amphi/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>AMPHI&lt;/strong> is a project that tackles a well-known and frustrating problem in the world of live events: &lt;strong>non-transparent secondary ticketing, scalping, and bot activity&lt;/strong> that harm fans, artists, and organizers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-solution-nft-tickets-on-blockchain">The Solution: NFT Tickets on Blockchain&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The core idea of AMPHI is to transform event tickets into &lt;strong>Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs)&lt;/strong> managed on a blockchain (currently tested on Polygon Amoy). This approach allows for the introduction of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Transparency:&lt;/strong> Each ticket is unique, and its history (issuance, ownership transfers) is traceable on-chain.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Control:&lt;/strong> Rules can be implemented directly in the ticket&amp;rsquo;s smart contract or the marketplace to limit unfair practices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Possibilities:&lt;/strong> NFTs open doors to additional experiences for fans (digital collectibles, exclusive content, loyalty mechanisms).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="the-mvp-minimum-viable-product">The MVP (Minimum Viable Product)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I have developed a working &lt;strong>MVP (Minimum Viable Product) / Demo&lt;/strong> that demonstrates the core functionalities:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AMPHI: Ticketing NFT &amp; P2P Marketplace</title><link>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/it/it/progetti/amphi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 21:21:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://modernage12.github.io/lorenzosnotes/it/it/progetti/amphi/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>AMPHI&lt;/strong> è un progetto che affronta un problema noto e frustrante nel mondo degli eventi dal vivo: il &lt;strong>secondary ticketing non trasparente, lo scalping e l&amp;rsquo;azione dei bot&lt;/strong> che danneggiano fan, artisti e organizzatori.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="la-soluzione-biglietti-nft-su-blockchain">La Soluzione: Biglietti NFT su Blockchain&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>L&amp;rsquo;idea centrale di AMPHI è trasformare i biglietti per eventi in &lt;strong>Non-Fungible Tokens (NFT)&lt;/strong> gestiti su blockchain (attualmente testato su Polygon Amoy). Questo approccio permette di introdurre:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Trasparenza:&lt;/strong> Ogni biglietto è unico e la sua storia (emissione, passaggi di proprietà) è tracciabile on-chain.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Controllo:&lt;/strong> È possibile implementare regole direttamente nello smart contract del biglietto o nel marketplace per limitare pratiche scorrette.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Nuove Possibilità:&lt;/strong> Gli NFT aprono le porte a esperienze aggiuntive per i fan (collezionabili digitali, contenuti esclusivi, meccanismi di loyalty).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="lmvp-minimum-viable-product">L&amp;rsquo;MVP (Minimum Viable Product)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ho sviluppato un &lt;strong>MVP (Minimum Viable Product) / Demo funzionante&lt;/strong> che dimostra le funzionalità core:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>